Guide to the Student Protest Collection, 1965-1980 MS2093
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Student Protest Collection
1965-1980
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2093
1.5 Linear Feet
Collection consists of flyers, leaflets, and pamphlets documenting the war in Indochina, welfare, politics, humanitarian aid, civil rights, and The George Washington University administrative actions between 1965 and 1980.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Student Protest Collection reflects the various activities that were connected with student activism in the Washington, D.C. area from 1965 to 1980. Some records specifically concern the activities at the George Washington University during this period.
Collection Scope and Content
The Student Protest Collection spans the years 1965 to 1980, with the bulk of the material falling between 1969 and 1972. The collection consists of flyers, leaflets, and pamphlets. The subject matter is quite varied. Topics include the war in Indochina, welfare, politics, humanitarian aid, civil rights, and The George Washington University administrative actions.
Collection Organization
This collection is organized into four series. They include chronological; subject; newspaper articles and Lucy McMahon materials.
Welfare reform; Civil rights; Indochinese War; Humanitarian assistance; Washington (D.C.); Political activists; George Washington University
- Chronological, 1965-1980; MS2093 Series 1; .5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of all dated materials relating to student protests in Washington, DC.
  - Chronological material, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chronological material, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chronological material, 1970 January - May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chronological material, 1970 June - August (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronological material, 1970 September - December (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chronological material, 1971 January - April (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chronological material, 1971 May - December (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chronological material, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chronological material, 1973 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Subject, 1965-1980; MS2093 Series 2; .5 Linear feet
  This series consists of all undated materials relating to student protests in Washington, DC. Subjects such as civil rights, war in Southeast Asia, welfare, and the George Washington University administration are represented in this series.
  - Big Business / Capitalism, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Civil Rights / Liberties, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ecology, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University Administration, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nixon Impeachment, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Nuclear Power, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Police Harassment, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Political Radicalism, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Religion, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - War in Indochina / Southeast Asia, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Welfare / Humanitarian Aid, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - International Events, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, Circa 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Maury Hall Takeover Hearing - first day, 1969 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Maury Hall Takeover Hearing - second day, 1969 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Newspaper Articles, 1965-1980; MS2093 Series 3; .5 Linear feet
  This series consists of newspaper articles from Washington, DC which pertain to student activism in the DC area. Also included are pertinent editions of the Hatchet, the Advocate, and the Monday Report, George Washington University publications. A list of citations for newspaper articles on student activism is included as well.
  - Newspaper Articles, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Lucy McMahon materials, 1971-1973; MS2093 Series 4; .5 Linear Feet 1 document box
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains protest materials collected by Lucy Domin McMahon, BA '74, while a student at George Washington University. Materials include May Day Tactical Manual, "Road to San Diego Phase 1: Nixon Eviction", Washington Area Peace Coalition march flyer, The Daily Rag "Handbook to Inaugural Actions", Vol. III Nos. 19 and 20 of Quicksilver Times, a March on Washington button, Newsweek clippings, and a 1973 tourist map of Washington, D.C.
  - Lucy McMahon records, 1971-1973; Series 4 Box 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)